Mikael Bengt Erik Fallesen

mfallesen2010@gmail.com | cell: (425) 908-0342

Full stack developer with 2 years of professional experience building and designing websites and applications for clients with a heavy emphasis on front end technologies. And an army combat veteran with a proven track record of group collaboration and mission focus.

Education

BA of Arts English Literature, Thomas Edison State College, NJ

University of Washington Full Stack Developer Certification, WA

Skills

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Node.js, jQuery, Python, MySQL,

Experience

CodeSwede.com 2019 – present: Freelancer

- Freelance full stack developer Creating custom web apps, websites, CMS integration, and back end work.
- Work directly with clients to ensure technologies are meeting their needs.
- Manage client expectations to provide products within a reasonable timeframe.

Codesqwerl.com 2016 – 2019: Entry Level Developer

- Entry level developer responsible for maintaining existing client sites and building new sites and web apps for clients. Built, tested, and deployed Web sites and web apps according to client and product manager specifications.
- Worked with a mentor to quickly onboard with company policies and practices to deliver products to clients with minimal delay.
- Utilized existing libraries or developed custom solutions where appropriate.

US Security Associates 2010 – 2015: Director of Security

 Maintained access systems, cctv recorders, and resident portal in addition to additional duties.

US Army 2003 -2010: Squad Leader

- Heavy emphasis on transitioning from hard copy to incorporate modern web based technologies in both platoon, company, and even brigade level for administrative and logistical tasks.
- Infantry Non Commissioned Officer in the US Army in charge of managing soldiers, meeting leadership objectives, and ensuring smooth operation at every applicable unit level.